# Edwin Espinoza

(760) 215-0969 • espined48@gmail.com • edwin-espinoza.com

### **Professional Summary**

Graduate from Humboldt State University with a B.S. in computer science and an applied mathematics minor. Experience with building basic RESTful web services, websites and other computer applications. Held two tutoring positions while studying at Humboldt State University. Currently looking into transitioning to a programming position. Have previous experience in computer science and math tutoring with over 4 years of experience in STEM instruction. An encouraging tutor who provides productive feedback and implements effective learning strategies to help students succeed.

### **Education**

**Humboldt State University** - Arcata, CA **Bachelor's Degree:** 2020 Computer Science B.S. Applied Mathematics Minor

- Recipient of Kieval transfer Scholarship
- Member of the chess club
- Member of the computer science club

High School Diploma: 2012

San Marcos High School - San Marcos, CA

Palomar College - San Marcos, CA

#### Skills

- Analytical problem solving
- Research skills
- Self-motivated
- Program Languages: Oracle SQL, Linux, PHP, Javascript, HTML, CSS,
- Other technologies: Bootstrap, Mongodb, Nodejs, Semantic UI.
- English
- Spanish
- American sign language

### **Work History**

# General Tutor (middle school and high school), 08/2018 to Current Humboldt State University – Arcata, CA

I would drive to different school sites that have TRIO Talent Search students. I had to be able to work without supervision and help students with math between 6th and 8th grade. I also ran a coding club at one of the local middle schools, which helped students do an hour of code to understand programming and technology. I held structured meetings to discuss STEM summer programs to get students interested in STEM fields, as well as developed lessons and lesson plans for students.

# Computer Science Tutor, 01/2019 to Current Humboldt State University – Arcata, CA

Helped university students with their assignments and understanding of computer science concepts. Responsible for tracking student usage of tutoring services, and creating a friendly and studious environment for students to work in.

### **Math Tutor**, 06/2016 to 08/2018

## Palomar Community College District - San Marcos, CA

I would make appointments with students for up to an hour to help the students with their math problems. I had to learn and understand the many different backgrounds and cultures students came from to help understand their learning styles. I also had to manage time with the students, as well as watch for walk-in students who did not have appointments.

## Accomplishments

Published Characteristics of Light: velocity, massless energy and special relativity by Richard Sauerheber and Edwin Espinoza.

Helped establish a coding club in the after school program at Zane Middle School in Eureka, CA, which led to the program getting a grant.

Research Experience for Undergraduates funded by the National Science Foundation. I conducted research on kernel level malware detection on Linux systems.

#### References

Dr. Richard Sauerheber: Co-worker, Tutor, Researcher, Ph.D. Chemistry from University of CA, San Diego

Phone: (760) 744-1150 x2448 E-mail: <u>rsauerheber@palomar.edu</u>

Dr. Bori Mazzag (current employer): Supervisor, Chair of Mathematics & Computer Science

Ph.D. Applied Mathematics from University of CA, Davis

Phone: (707) 826-4952 E-mail: borim@humboldt.edu

Rose Sita Francia (current employer): Supervisor, M.A. in Educational Leadership, TRIO Talent Search Director and Collaboration Lead

Phone: (707) 826-4791

E-mail: <u>rose.francia@humboldt.edu</u>